Finding Aid for the Jonathan Friedlander Collection of Middle Eastern Americana LSC.1314
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Sheet Music, 1887 - 1967; 1 oversize box
  - Baubles, bangles and beads New York, NY: Frank Music Corporation., 1953; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Baubles, bangles and beads New York, NY: Frank Music Corporation., 1953; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Bo-la-bo Egyptian fox trot song New York: M. Witmark & Sons., 1919; 1 score (5 pages), 32 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 7)
    Creator: Fairman, George, 1881-1962
    First line: "Bo-la-bo, Bo-la-bo, oh, my heart is beating fast, far across the desert sand you come to claim my love at last."
  - Burning sands oriental fox trot New York, NY: Richmond-Robbins., 1922; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Creator: Meskill, Jack, 1897-
    First line: "Down by the sil'vry shores of the Nile, down where the Iris blooms all the while."
  - Burning sands oriental fox trot New York, NY: Richmond-Robbins., 1922; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Creator: Savino, Domenico, 1882-1973
  - Chariot race, or Ben Hur march New York, NY: E.T. Paull Music Company., 1894; 1 score (8 pages), 27 x 35 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Creator: Paull, E. T, 1858-1924
  - Chariot race, or Ben Hur march New York, NY: E.T. Paull Music Company., 1894; 1 score (8 pages), 27 x 35 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Creator: Wallace, Lew, 1827-1905
  - Chariot race, or Ben-Hur march New York, NY: E.T. Paull Music Company., 1894; 1 score (7 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Chariot race, or Ben-Hur march New York, NY: E.T. Paull Music Company., 1894; 1 score (7 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Chong (he come from Hong Kong) New York: Leo Feist Incorporated., 1919; 1 score (4 pages), 28 x 20 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 11)
    Creator: Weeks, Harold, 1893-1967
    First line: "Little Allee Fo Chong played all day in an oriental way, in a swell Chinese Cafe."
  - Ciribiribin Philadelphia, PA: Morris Music Company., 1909; 1 score (5 pages), 34 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 12)
    Creator: Thaler, Rudolf
    First line: "When through dale and vale I'm wandr'ing, only one name follows me, and while list'ning to its rhythm to my ear 'tis melody."
  - Ciribiribin Philadelphia, PA: Morris Music Company., 1909; 1 score (5 pages), 34 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 12)
    Creator: Pestalozza, A, 1851-1934
  - C-o-n-s-t-a-n-t-i-n-o-p-l-e New York, NY: de Sylva, Brown and Henderson, Incorporated., 1925; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 13)
    Creator: Carlton, Harry, 1904-
    Excerpt from lyrics reads: "You may laugh at Tommy Tomkins 'cause he couldn't spell Constantinople, but wait and see if there's anyone who thinks that they can do it well."
  - C-o-n-s-t-a-n-t-i-n-o-p-l-e New York, NY: de Sylva, Brown and Henderson, Incorporated., 1925; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - C-o-n-s-t-a-n-t-i-n-o-p-l-e New York, NY: de Sylva, Brown and Henderson, Incorporated., 1925; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 13)
    Creator: Weiss, Joseph M.
  - Constantly New York, NY: Paramount Music., 1942; 1 score (3 pages), 32 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 14)
    Creator: Burke, Johnny
    First line: "There I was what a sad affair I was, my heart was hitched to a dream." Cover is a promotional photo featuring Bob Hope in a turban, Bing Crosby in a fez, and Dorothy Lamour in oriental costume, taken from the motion picture Road to Morocco.
  - Constantly New York, NY: Paramount Music., 1942; 1 score (3 pages), 32 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 14)
    Creator: Van Heusen, Jimmy
  - Dardanella New York, NY: McCarthy & Fisher Company., 1923; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 3 copies (Box 19, Folder 15)
    Creator: Fisher, Fred, 1875-1942
    First line: "Down by the Dardanella Bay, where Oriental breezes play, there lives a lonesome maid Armenian."
  - Dardanella New York, NY: McCarthy & Fisher Company., 1923; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 3 copies (Box 19, Folder 15)
    Creator: Black, Johnny S.
  - Dardanella New York, NY: McCarthy & Fisher Company., 1923; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 3 copies (Box 19, Folder 15)
    Creator: DeTakacs, André
  - Dardanella New York, NY: McCarthy & Fisher Company., 1923; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 3 copies (Box 19, Folder 15)
    Creator: Bernard, Felix, 1897-1944
  - Dardanella New York, NY: Mills Music, Incorporated., 1928; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 16)
    First line: "Down by the Dardanella Bay, where Oriental breezes play, there lives a lonesome maid Armenian." Cover is pink and features a photo of Joan Brooks.
  - Dardanella New York, NY: Mills Music, Incorporated., 1928; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Dardanella New York, NY: Mills Music, Incorporated., 1928; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Dardanella New York, NY: Mills Music, Incorporated., 1928; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 17)
    First line: "Down by the Dardanella Bay, where Oriental breezes play, there lives a lonesome maid Armenian." Cover is blue and beige and features a photo of The Townsmen.
  - Dardanella New York, NY: Mills Music, Incorporated., 1928; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Dardanella New York, NY: Mills Music, Incorporated., 1928; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Desert dreams: fox trot New York, NY: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder., 1920; 1 score (5 pages), 32 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 18)
    Creator: Lewin, Leonard
    First line: "Oh the minute that I close my eyes, I'm under Asia Minor skies."
  - Desert song New York, NY: Harms Incorporated., 1926; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 2 copies (Box 19, Folder 19)
    Creator: Harbach, Otto
    First line: "My desert is waiting, dear, come there with me." Cover is yellow and blue and features an illustration of a man carrying a woman through the desert.
  - Desert song New York, NY: Harms Incorporated., 1926; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 2 copies (Box 19, Folder 19)
    Creator: Hammerstein, Oscar
  - Desert song New York, NY: Harms Incorporated., 1926; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 2 copies (Box 19, Folder 19)
    Creator: Romberg, Sigmund
  - Desert song New York, NY: Harms Incorporated., 1926; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 3 copies (Box 19, Folder 20)
    First line: "My desert is waiting, dear, come there with me." Cover is blue and purple and features an illustration of people on camels.
  - Desert song New York, NY: Harms Incorporated., 1926; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 3 copies (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Desert song New York, NY: Harms Incorporated., 1926; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 3 copies (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Desert song New York, NY: Harms Incorporated., 1926; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 21)
    First line: "My desert is waiting, dear, come there with me." Cover is black and white.
  - Desert song New York, NY: Harms Incorporated., 1926; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Desert song New York, NY: Harms Incorporated., 1926; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Dust on the moon: melody fox-trot New York, NY: E. B. Marks Music., 1934; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 22)
    Creator: Lecuona, Ernesto, 1896-1963
    Cover is indigo and yellow and features a photograph of Teddy Black.
  - Dust on the moon: melody fox-trot New York, NY: E. B. Marks Music., 1934; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 22)
    Creator: Adams, Stanley, 1907-
  - Egypt you and I New York, NY: Jerome H. Remick & Company., 1923; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 23)
    Creator: Alden, John
    First line: "Fond mem'ries seem to sing and bring back an oriental spring to me."
  - Egypt you and I New York, NY: Jerome H. Remick & Company., 1923; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 23)
    Creator: Kahn, Gus
  - Exodus: main theme piano solo New York, NY: Chappell & Company., 1960; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 2 copies (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Hava nagila: concert style arrangement North Hollywood, CA: Hall Publications., 1967; 1 score (9 pages), 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 25)
    Creator: Axel, Alexander
  - Hooray for love: fox-trot New York, NY: Melrose Music., 1948; 1 score (5 pages), 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 26)
    Creator: Arlen, Harold, 1905-1986
    First line: "Here's to my best romance, here's to my worst romance, here's to my first romance ages ago."
  - Hooray for love: fox-trot New York, NY: Melrose Music., 1948; 1 score (5 pages), 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 26)
    Creator: Robin, Leo
  - I wish I were Aladdin New York, NY: Crawford Music Corporation., 1935; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 27)
    Creator: Gordon, Mack, 1904-1959
    Excerpt from chorus reads: "I wish I were Aladdin how lucky I would be, I'd rub my little lamp and wish that you would fall in love with me."
  - I wish I were Aladdin New York, NY: Crawford Music Corporation., 1935; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 27)
    Creator: Revel, Harry, 1905-1958
  - I wish I were Aladdin New York, NY: Crawford Music Corporation., 1935; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - I wish I were Aladdin New York, NY: Crawford Music Corporation., 1935; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - I'll say she does New York, NY: Jerome H. Remick & Company., 1918; 1 score (5 pages), 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 28)
    Creator: Kahn, Gus, 1886-1941
    First line: "I've got a brand new sweetie better than the one before oh! she's got ev'rything and a little bit more."
  - I'll say she does New York, NY: Jerome H. Remick & Company., 1918; 1 score (5 pages), 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 28)
    Creator: De Sylva, B. G. 1896-1950
  - I'll say she does New York, NY: Jerome H. Remick & Company., 1918; 1 score (5 pages), 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 28)
    Creator: Jolson, Al
  - In a Persian market intermezzo-scene New York, NY: Bosworth & Company., 1920; 1 score (11 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 29)
    Creator: Ketèlbey, Albert W. 1875-1959
  - In my harem New York, NY: Waterson, Berlin, & Snyder., 1913; 1 score (5 pages), 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 30)
    Creator: Berlin, Irving, 1888-
    Excerpt from lyrics reads: "When the Turks were called away to war, a Turk asked Patrick if he wouldn't watch his harem, Patrick said, 'With pleasure, I will cover ev'ry track, I'll take care of ev'rything, so don't you hurry back.'"
  - Just a little drink (a song with a kick) San Francisco, CA: Villa Morét., 1925; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 2 copies (Box 19, Folder 31)
    Creator: Gay, Byron
    First line: 'Way out on the desert, not a drop to drink."
  - Lily of the nile New York, NY: Leo E. Berliner & Company., ca. 1900s; 1 score (5 pages), 36 x 28 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 32)
    Creator: Berliner, Leo
  - Love songs of the Nile: featured in Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer's production The barbarian New York, NY: Robbins Music Corporation., 1933; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 33)
    Creator: Brown, Nacio Herb, 1896-
    First line: "Allah smiling on high, moonbeams cover the sky, stars gleam giving us light, Allah cheers the night."
  - Love songs of the Nile: featured in Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer's production The barbarian New York, NY: Robbins Music Corporation., 1933; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 33)
    Creator: Freed, Arthur, 1894-
  - Love songs of the Nile: featured in Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer's production The barbarian New York, NY: Robbins Music Corporation., 1933; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 33)
    Creator: Novarro, Ramon, 1899-1968
  - March across the desert: descriptive fantasia London: F. Pitman Hart & Company Limited., undated; 1 score (7 pages), 35 x 25 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 34)
    Creator: Pridham, John, 1818-1896
  - Misirlou New York, NY: Colonial Music., 1941; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 35)
    Creator: Roubanis, N.
    First line: "Desert shadows creep across purple sands, natives kneel in prayer by their caravans."
  - My song of the Nile New York, NY: M. Witmark & Sons., 1929; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters, 3 copies (Box 19, Folder 36)
    Creator: Bryan, Alfred, 1871-1958
    First line: "I have built a pyramid of dreams, where the Star of Allah brightly beams." Cover is blue, white and black and features a photograph of Richard Berthelmess.
  - My song of the Nile New York, NY: M. Witmark & Sons., 1929; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters, 3 copies (Box 19, Folder 36)
    Creator: Meyer, George W, 1884-1959
  - Old King Tut: in old King Tutenkhamen's day New York, NY: H. Von Tilzer., 1923; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 2 copies (Box 19, Folder 37)
    Creator: Von Tilzer, Harry, 1872-1946
    First line: "Three thousand years ago, in history we know, King Tutenkhamen ruled a mighty land."
  - Old King Tut: in old King Tutenkhamen's day New York, NY: H. Von Tilzer., 1923; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters, 2 copies (Box 19, Folder 37)
    Creator: Jerome, William
  - Oriental intermezzo San Francisco, CA: Daniels & Wilson Incorporated., 1917; 1 score (3 pages), 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 38)
    Creator: Rose, Vincent, 1880-1944
  - Out of the East: Oriental fox trot Detroit, MI: Jerome H. Remick & Company., undated; 1 score (4 pages), 28 x 35 centimeters, color photocopy (Box 19, Folder 39)
    Cover features illustration of woman dancing in front of pyramids and palm trees with a dark blue background.
  - Out of the East: song Detroit, MI: Jerome H. Remick & Company., undated; 1 score (4 pages), 23 x 31 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 40)
    Creator: Havez, Jean C.
    Cover features illustration of woman dancing in front of pyramids and palm trees with a blue background.
  - Out of the East: song Detroit, MI: Jrome H. Remick & Company., undated; 1 score (4 pages), 23 x 31 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Palesteena: Lena from Palesteena New York, NY: Shapiro, Bernstein & Company., 1920; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 41)
    Creator: Conrad, Con, 1891-1938
    First line: "In the Bronx of New York City lives a girl, she's not so pretty."
  - Palesteena: Lena from Palesteena New York, NY: Shapiro, Bernstein & Company., 1920; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 41)
    Creator: Robinson, J. Russel
  - Persian lamb rag: a pepperette Boston, MA: Walter Jacobs., 1908; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 42)
    Creator: Wenrich, Percy, 1887-1952
  - Persian rug San Francisco, CA: Villa Moret., 1927; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 43)
    First verse: "In the distant East, there is a legend old, I am told, of a Persian rug, worth all its weight in gold."
  - Persian rug San Francisco, CA: Villa Moret., 1927; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 43)
    Creator: Moret, Neil, 1878-1943
  - Rose of Egyptland New York, NY: M. Witmark & Sons., 1919; 1 score (5 pages), 30 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 44)
    Creator: Freeman, Harold B
    First line: "Where the Nile is flowing, 'mid the poppies growing, the shades of night are softly falling, how my heart is yearning."
  - Sal-O-May New York, NY: E. B. Marks Music., ca. 1920; 1 score, 9 x 12 inches, mounted color photocopy (Box 19, Folder 45)
    Creator: Stolz, Robert
    From cover: "song of the Orient and fox-trot."
  - Sal-O-May New York, NY: E. B. Marks Music., ca. 1920; 1 score, 9 x 12 inches, mounted color photocopy (Box 19, Folder 45)
    Creator: Costello, Bartley
  - San New York, NY: L. B. Curtis., 1923; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 46)
    Creator: McPhail, Lindsay, 1895-1965
    First line: "King San of Senegal sat on the shore at Bulamay, Bulamay."
  - Sheik of Araby New York, NY: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Company., 1921; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 47)
    Creator: Wheeler, Francis
    First line: "Over the desert wild and free rides the bold Sheik of Araby." Pages missing.
  - Sheik of Araby New York, NY: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Company., 1921; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 47)
    Creator: Snyder, Ted, 1881-1965
  - Sheik of Araby New York, NY: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder Company., 1921; 1 score (5 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 47)
    Creator: Smith, Harry Bache, 1860-1936
  - Soko: Moorish march Detroit, MI: Whitney Warner Publishing Company., 1903; 1 score (7 pages), 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 48)
    Creator: Arnold, John
  - Sword is my sweetheart true., undated; 1 score (4 pages), 20 x 27 centimeters, color photocopy (Box 19, Folder 49)
    Creator: Hoffman, Max
    Music from the musical comedy The Young Turk.
  - Sword is my sweetheart true., undated; 1 score (4 pages), 20 x 27 centimeters, color photocopy (Box 19, Folder 49)
    Creator: Williams, Harry
  - Tripoli: on the shores of Tripoli New York, NY: M. Witmark & Sons., 1920; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 50)
    Creator: Dubin, Al
    First line: "Open the portals of memory, let the old honeymoon glow; take me again to old Tripoli, bring back the sweet long ago."
  - Tripoli: on the shores of Tripoli New York, NY: M. Witmark & Sons., 1920; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 50)
    Creator: Cunningham, Paul, 1890-1960
  - Tripoli: on the shores of Tripoli New York, NY: M. Witmark & Sons., 1920; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 50)
    Creator: Weill, Irving, 1894-
  - Turkish march (Marcia alla turca) Chicago, IL: McKinley Music Company., undated; 1 score (7 pages), 31 x 23 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 51)
    Creator: Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791.
    Caption from introductory remarks reads, "Mozart lived close enough to Turkey to be familiar with its music, so we may accept this little march as picturing the style of oriental music in the latter part of the 18th century." No linguistic content.
  - Vashti characteristique Cincinnati, OH: The Fillmore Brothers., 1904; 1 score (5 pages), 33 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 52)
    Creator: Fillmore, Henry, 1881-1956
  - Vision of Salome: valse orientale New York, NY: T.B. Harms & Francis, Day, & Hunter., 1909; 1 score (9 pages), 35 x 27 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 53)
    Creator: Joyce, Archibald, 1873-1963
  - You belong to me Hollywood, CA: Ridgeway Music., 1952; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 54)
    Creator: Stewart, Redd
    First line: "See the pyramids along the Nile, watch the sunrise on a tropic isle." Cover is red and white and features a photo of Jo Stafford.
  - You belong to me Hollywood, CA: Ridgeway Music., 1952; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 54)
    Creator: King, Pee Wee, 1914-
  - You belong to me Hollywood, CA: Ridgeway Music., 1952; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - You belong to me Hollywood, CA: Ridgeway Music., 1952; 1 score (3 pages), 31 x 24 centimeters (Box 19, Folder 54)
    Creator: Price, Chilton
- Motion Picture Films, ca. 1975 - 2004; 6 boxes, 1 oversize box (3 linear feet)
  This series consists of motion pictures and feature animation including representations and themes of the Middle East in DVD, Laserdisc, and VHS format.
  - DVDs, 1995 - 2004; 4 boxes (2 linear feet)
    - Adventure in Iraq Warner Brothers Pictures, 2004., 1943; 1 videodisc (64 minutes): sound, black & white, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Creator: Ledermand, D. Ross
      Role: director
      Front cover reads: "Death and Danger in the Desert."
    - Aladdin: platinum edition Disney, 2004., 1992; 2 videodiscs (90 minutes): sound, color, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Creator: Musker, John
      Back cover reads: "In the heart of an enchanted city, a commoner named Aladdin and his mischievous monkey Abu battle to save the free-spirited Princess Jasmine from the schemes of the evil sorcerer Jafar. Aladdin's whole life changes with one rub of a magic lamp as a fun-loving, shape-shifting Genie appears and grants him three wishes, setting him on an incredible journey of discovery."
    - Aladdin: platinum edition Disney, 2004., 1992; 2 videodiscs (90 minutes): sound, color, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Creator: Clements, Ron
    - Arabian nights Artisan Entertainment, 2000., 1999; 1 videodisc (179 minutes): sound, color, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Creator: Barron, Steve
      Based on the classic store "A Thousand and One Nights," this lavish production brings to life some of the most timeless fables to come down though the ages. A legendary heroine, Scheherazade, saves her kingdom and her own life by seducing her husband Schahriar's imagination with the fantastical tales of Aladdin, Ali Baba, other larger-than-life heroes, warriors, and djinns."
    - Beast Columbia Pictures, 2003., 1988; 1 videodisc (110 minutes): sound, color, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Creator: Reynolds, Kevin
      Back cover reads: "Afghanistan, 1981, and the Soviet Union is locked in a futile and bloody battle with the Mujaheddin guerillas."
    - Bram Stoker's the mummy Goldbar Entertainment., 1997; 1 videodisc (100 minutes): sound, color, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Creator: Obrow, Jeffrey
    - Captain Gallant of the foreign legion (volume 1) Alpha Video, 2005., 1955; 1 videodisc (179 minutes): sound, black & white, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Creator: Yarbrough, Jean
      Back cover reads: "In the harsh desert of North Africa, Captain Michael Gallant of the Foreign Legion is stationed on a peacekeeping mission. While gangs and bandits disrupt local villages, Gallant commands a post of well-trained Legionnaires, leading them into battle and delivering justice wherever it is needed."
    - Cartoon craze presents: Felix the Cat Digiview Productions, 2004., undated; 1 videodisc (75 minutes): sound, color, black & white, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Episode Four: "Felix in Arabiantics."
    - Cleopatra Artisan Entertainment., 1999; 1 videodisc (177 minutes): sound, color, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Creator: Roddam, Franc
      Back cover reads: "For over two-thousand years, the legend of the beautiful Queen of the Nile has stirred the imagination..."
    - David and Goliath Alpha Video, 2003., 1960; 1 videodisc (92 minutes): sound, color, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Creator: Baldi, Francisco
    - David and Goliath Alpha Video, 2003., 1960; 1 videodisc (92 minutes): sound, color, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Creator: Pottier, Richard
    - English patient Miramax., 1996; 2 videodiscs (162 minutes): sound, color, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Creator: Minghella, Anthony
    - Exodus Metro Goldwyn Mayer, 2002., 1960; 1 videodisc (198 minutes): sound, color, 4 3/4 inches (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Creator: Preminger, Otto